Guide to the Stanford University Map Collection SC1049
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Maps
  - Campus Miscellany, Series 7; 68 item(s)
    - Inner quadrangle, front portions of outer quadrangle completed when map drawn; identifies departments in each structure, locates faculty residences and fraternal houses and identifies occupants., btwn. 1899-1902; M600 (Box D3)
    - Stanford University, California Civilian Defense areas for use of air raid wardens., 1941; M601 (Box C2)
    - Map, Leland Stanford Junior University and campus., 1910 or after; M602 (Box Na1)
    - No title, date, or other identifying information. University land identified as Leland Stanford University Trust., 1889?; M603 (Box Na1)
    - Map of arboretum, L.S.J.U., March 1916; M604 (Box Na2)
    - Planting scheme for sunken panels, main building group, Stanford University. G.A. Dailey, landscape engineer., 189-?; M605 (Box Na2)
    - [Planting scheme for arboretum]., undated; M606 (Box Na2)
    - [Planting Scheme for arboretum]., undated; M607 (Box Na2)
    - [Planting scheme on Serra Street between Lomita and Palou]., undated; M608 (Box D3)
    - Planting scheme for trees (1964-67-79-72) on Campus Drive - Serra St. to Escondido Rd. Stanford University. W.E. Parker, Arborist., undated; M609 (Box A1)
    - Stanford Linear Accelerator. Schematic site plan., 196-?; M620 (Box A1)
    - Existing vehicular traffic circulation system. A circulation and parking program for Stanford University. Stanford planning office., 1959; M621 (Box Na2)
    - Map number 2 of the San Juan subdivision extention in the lands of Leland Stanford Jr. University., Feb.-Mar., 1914; M622 (Box Na2)
    - Plot showing Toe-of-Slope on location thru Stanford., July 30, 1907; M630 (Box D3)
    - Peninsular Railroad Co. Profile of Proposed location through the land of L.S.J.U., Aug. 3, 1907; M631 (Box C2)
    - Peninsular Railroad Co. Standard Roadbed., Aug. 10, 1907; M632 (Box A1)
    - Peninsular Railroad Co. Profile of Proposed Location through L.S.J.U. Property., Apr. 25, 1907; M633 (Box D3)
    - Peninsular Railroad Co. Sketch showing Property Required at entrance to Stanford University., Sept. 12, 1907; M634 (Box A1)
    - Peninsular Railroad Co. Front Elevation Standard Double 20 ft. Culvert with Center Pier., Sept. 26, 1907; M635 (Box C2)
    - [Map of Peninsular Railroad through the lands of L.S.J.U.]., [1907]; M636 (Box Na2)
    - [White print map showing locations of different lines for proposed railroads passing through the University property.], [1907]; M637 (Box D3)
    - [Traffic] Circulation study. Planning Office, Stanford University. Shows present needs and final peripheral system., Dec., 1948; M638 (Box D3)
    - Alignment of Santa Teresa. Planning Office, Stanford University., Dec. 6, 1948; M639 (Box Na2)
    - Map of Alta Vista, Charles G. Lathrop's Residence Grounds. Unsigned., 1908; M640 os (Box Na2)
    - Map of Alta Vista, Charles G. Lathrop's Residence Grounds. Unsigned., M640a
    - Map of Alta Vista, Charles G. Lathrop's Residence Grounds. Unsigned., M640b (Box C2)
    - Map of Alta Vista, Charles G. Lathrop's Residence Grounds. Unsigned., M640c
    - Map of Rock Quarry, Leland Stanford Junior University. A.J. Bain., undated; M641 (Box Na2)
    - Map showing elevations about Quarry in the lands of the Leland Stanford Junior University. Herrmann Brothers., 1917; M642 (Box D3)
    - Plan of the Proposed Lagunita Subdivision. Herrmann Brothers., 1915; M643 (Box Na2)
    - Map #1 of the Lagunita Subdivision. Herrmann Brothers., 1916; M644 (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Upper Section of an enlargement of Map #1 of the Lagunita Subdivision. Herrmann Brothers., 1916; M644a os
    - Section Enlargement Map: Middle Section of an enlargement of Map #1 of the Lagunita Subdivision. Herrmann Brothers., 1916; M644b os
    - Section Enlargement Map: Lower Section of an enlargement of Map #1 of the Lagunita Subdivision. Herrmann Brothers., 1916; M644c os
    - Lagunita Subdivision. Herrmann Brothers., 1917; M645 (Box Na2)
    - Laurence Frost Memorial Amphitheatre: North Sheet of Two Plane Table Sheets. Unsigned., 1936-37; M646 (Box Na2)
    - Laurence Frost Memorial Amphitheatre: South Sheet of Two Plane Table Sheets. Unsigned., 1936-37; M647 (Box Na2)
    - Plat of Cedro Cottage and Grounds at Leland Stanford University. W.G. Utschig., 1906; M648 (Box D3)
    - Cedro Cottage, Stadia Survey for Proposed Fox Farm. Unsigned., 1930; M649 (Box B1)
    - Cedro Cottage Grounds, Stadia Survey. Unsigned., 1937; M650 (Box A1)
    - Block Map: Roble Gymnasium, Illumination Laboratory, Press and Mining Facilities, Corner of Santa Teresa and Lomita Drive. Unsigned., Pre-1906; M651 (Box Na2)
    - Block Map: Roble Gymnasium, Illumination Laboratory, Press and Mining Facilities, Sequoia Hall, Corner of Santa Teresa and Lomita Drive. Unsigned., Pre-1906; M652 (Box Na2)
    - Block Map: Frost Amphitheater, Power Plant, Memorial Hall. Unsigned., 1924; M653 (Box Na2)
    - Block Map: Museum, Medicine Building. Unsigned., 1925; M654 (Box Na2)
    - Block Map: Chemistry Building, Medicine Building, Museum. Unsigned., 1925; M655 os
    - Untitled map showing mausoleum and mausoleum grounds landscaping plans. Unsigned., undated; M656 (Box Na2)
    - Junipero Serra Boulevard: Working map showing chain positions, turns, and other survey reference points. Unsigned., early 1930s; M660 (Box D3)
    - Junipero Serra Boulevard: Proposed link between Mayfield and Old Foothill Road showing faculty lots. Unsigned., early 1930s; M661 (Box D3)
    - Junipero Serra Boulevard and Stanford Avenue Extension: Working map showing campus coordinates based on center of County Road Bridge. Unsigned, early 1930s; M662 (Box Na2)
    - Junipero Serra Boulevard Change Alignment. Detailed enlargement upon unconstructed section of Boulevard (see Map 662). Unsigned., early 1930s; M663 (Box Na2)
    - Junipero Serra Boulevard: Working map showing proposed Boulevard from Page Mill Road to Lake Lagunita. Unsigned., early 1930s; M664 (Box Na2)
    - Junipero Serra Boulevard, County Bridge to Page Mill Road. Map sheet also includes an unrelated plan for Convalescent Home Road in "North Palo Alto." Unsigned., early 1930s; M665 (Box Na2)
    - Frenchman's Hill Subdivision: Working map showing chain placement, turns, and other survey specifications. Unsigned., undated; M666 os
    - Untitled topographical map of Ryan Laboratory and vicinity, including Palo Alto Reservoir, Mayfield Avenue, and Junipero Serra Road. Unsigned., undated; M667 os
    - Map of a Resurvey of the Leland Stanford Junior University Campus, Santa Clara County, California: showing electrical lines, sewers, other utilities and lot specifications. Herrmann Brothers., 1915; M670 os
    - Landscaping / Tree-planting Maps. First leaf shows dates of landscaping projects on campus. Subsequent leaves represent enlargements of sections of first leaf, with tree and shrub types, etc. D.C. Schroder., 1969; M671 (Box Na2)
    - Proposed road improvements, Stanford University., 1943; M672 (Box Na2)
    - Palo Alto pipeline. El Camino and University Avenue., undated; M673 (Box Na2)
    - Parking plans., undated; M674 os
    - Sections of Ground around Tomb., Sept., 1888; M675 (Box Na2)
    - Cross Sections of Tomb Grounds., Sept., 1888; M676 (Box Na2)
    - [Cross Section of Tomb Grounds?], 1888?; M677 (Box Na2)
    - [Hoover Tower in Comparison to Other Towers.], circa 1940?; M680 (Box Na2)
    - Leland Stanford Junior University Planting Plan. F.L. Olmsted and C., Landscape Architects., Feb. 18, 1891; M681 (Box Na2)
    - The hermit mine [topographical maps of section of Jasper Ridge], 1922; M682 (Box C2)
    - Stanford University of the present and of the immediate future [in fundraising booklet published by the University], circa 1922; M683 (Box C2)
    - Topographic map of grounds - contours copied from lithograph of original by J.G. McMillan - 1886-87. Stanford University - Sept. 1908. Traced by S.M., M684 (Box C2)
    - Residential section of Stanford University, 1937/38; M685 (Box A1)
    - Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve: Vegetation Communities (verso: Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve: Trails). Copyright 1996 Center for Conservation Biology and JRBP, Stanford University., M686 (Box A1)
    - Trees in the Frost Amphitheatre Area, M687
    - Campus Circulation and Land Use. Stanford University. Eldridge T. Spencer Director of Planning., 1949-08; M689
    - University Buildings. Eldridge T. Spencer Director of Planning., 1949-09; M691
    - Proposed Land Use Map Stanford University, 1953-04-14; M692
      Stanford University. Planning Office
    - Proposed Land Use Map Stanford University, 1953-05-12; M693
    - Traffic survey - cars entering Stanford campus Friday, 1953. Eldridge T Spencer Director of Planning, 1953-08; M690
    - Plat showing surveys of portions of lands of LSJU lying within the limites of the Town of Mayfield. Surveyed at the request of the Town Board of Trustees. Surveyed Oct. 1-4, 1918, by W. H. Myrick., M695
      Myrick, W. H.
    - Tract 1959 Pine Hill No. 1 Santa Clara County, California. Being a subdivision of a portion of the lands of LSJU. Lawrence G. Brian, civil engineer., M696
    - Land Use Policy/Plan [from Livingston Blayney study]. Color coded map of land uses for entire University acreage., 1971; M697
      Livingston and Blayney
    - Map showing location of proposed athletic field Stanford University [surveyed and mapped by students], 1900-01; M698
    - Radio Field Sites of Stanford University and Stanford Research Institute, 1968 Oct 24; M818
  - Official Campus Maps, Series 8; 39 item(s)
    These maps include the 1908 survey of University lands in Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties requested by the Board of Trustees and various enlargements of sections of that map; similar surveys done in the 1950s; and various maps produced by the Planning Office.
    - Map of the lands of Leland Stanford Junior University at and near the site of the University and in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo, California, surveyed at the request of theBoard of Trustees, by A.T. F.A. Herrmann. Lithograph by Britton and Rey., Jul. to Nov., 1908; M700 (Box C2)
    - Map of the lands of Leland Stanford Junior University at and near the site of the University and in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo, California, surveyed at the request of the Board of Trustees, by A.T. F.A. Herrmann. Lithograph by Britton and Rey., Jul. to Nov., 1908; M700 (Box Na2)
    - Land Classification Map: Copy of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) color-coded to indicate differing kinds of hill land. Classification made with assistance of J.S. Witherell, General Superintendent. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700a (Box Na2)
    - Lot Demarcation Map: Copy of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) emphasizing lot boundaries by means of colored lines. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700b (Box Na2)
    - Transferable Land Map: Copy of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) showing alienable portions of the Stanford propery in blue-green. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700c (Box Na2)
    - Transferable Land Map: Copy of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) showing alienable portions of property in dark blue. [Note: this representation of alienable property differs slightly from that of M 700c]. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700d (Box Na2)
    - Lot Map of Stanford Campus: Working map traced from M 700 (Map of the Lands of LSJU...) with enlarged campus representation. Unsigned. Based on Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700e (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Upper Left Corner of M 700 (Map of the Lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700f (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Upper Left Midsection of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700g (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Upper Right Midsection of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700h (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Upper Right Corner of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700i (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Lower Left Corner of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700j (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Lower Left Midsection of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700k (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Lower Right Midsection of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700l (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Lower Right Corner of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700m (Box Na2)
    - Section Enlargement Map: Lower Right Corner of M 700 (Map of the lands of LSJU...) enlarged by approximately 12x in photoreproduction. Herrmann Brothers., 1908; M700n (Box Na2)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo., 195-?; M701 (Box D3)
    - [Stanford University lands.], circa 1955; M702 (Box Na2)
    - Stanford University campus, Santa Clara County, California. Proposed educational zone., 1959; M703 (Box Na2)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo. C.H. Maier., 1955; M704 (Box D3)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo. C.H. Maier., M704_1
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo. C.H. Maier., 1955; M704_2 (Box D3)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo. C.H. Maier., 1955; M704_3 (Box D3)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo. C.H. Maier., M704_4
    - Topographic survey of the lands of Stanford University, Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties, California. E. Elmore Hutchison. No. 5 of 14 sheets., March, 1951; M705a (Box Na3)
    - Topographic survey of the lands of Stanford University, Santa Clara and San Mateo counties, California. E. Elmore Hutchison. No. 8 of 14 sheets., March, 1951; M705b (Box Na3)
    - Topographic Survey of the lands of Stanford University, Santa Clara and San Mateo counties, California. E. Elmore Hutchison. No. 9 of 14 sheets., March, 1951; M705c (Box Na3)
    - Land use study. Plate IV., undated; M706 (Box Na3)
    - Land uses in academic reserve. Stanford Planning Office. Oscar Nelson., Nov. 28, 1958; M707 (Box Na3)
    - Stanford University Project M survey data map with test hole locations and elevations. Geo. S. Nolte., 1959?; M708 (Box Na3)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University in the counties of Santa Clara and San Mateo [showing alienable and inalienable property]., June 11, 1947; M709 (Box D3)
    - Topographical map of a region about Stanford University., 1920?; M710 (Box Na3)
    - Topographical map of a region about Stanford University., 1920?; M710a (Box C2)
    - Topographical map of a region about Stanford University., M710b
    - Map of Leland Stanford Junior University and Campus, showing University buildings, student residences, private homes, sewer, water and other utility lines. Unsigned (oversize), pre-1906; M711
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University. Prepared by the Stanford University Planning Office., 1968-01; M713 (Box Na3)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University. Prepared by the Stanford University Planning Office., M713b
      - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University. Prepared by the Stanford University Planning Office., M713a
    - Leland Stanford Junior University. Prepared by the Stanford University Planning Office., 1972-1973; M714 (Box D3)
    - Campus Land Use map; Stanford University, [ca. 1954]; M715 (Box D3)
    - Stanford Properties Master Plan Research: Industrial Area Rezoning, Sept. 1, 1953; M716 (Box Na3)
    - Stanford Lands: Palo Alto Annexation Acreage Analysis, April 28, 1954; M717 (Box Na3)
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University. Prepared by the S. U. Planning Office. Thoroughfare information to Livingston Blayney for Land Use Policy/Plan Study, Nov. 18, 1970; M718 (Box Na3)
    - Central Campus Master Plan. [Buildings are shown but focus is on landscaping], 1965; M719 (Box Na3)
    - Land Use Study. Stanford Properties Master Plan Research., 1953-1954; M720
    - Master Plan of Land Use. Showing existing leases and proposed zoning (?). Stanford University. Eldridge T. Spencer Director of Planning., 1950-09; M721
    - Sanitary Sewer Mains. Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1953-12-16; M722
      Skidmore, Owings & Merrill
    - Stanford University parking and circulation maps (transit map on reverse), 1969-2008; M723
    - Stanford Base Map. Quad numbers superimposed and color coordinated., M724
    - Street numbers Leland Stanford Junior University. Prepared by the Stanford University Planning Office, M725
  - Map Books, Series 9; 3 volume(s)
    There are three map books: a small volume of assorted lands owned by the Stanfords, c. 1869-1903; a block book for the campus, 1901-1903; and insurance maps for the campus, 1917.
    - Leland Stanford Junior University Insurance Maps, 1917 Oct; M801
    - Block book, Leland Stanford Junior University campus, 1901-1903; M802
    - Map book of Stanford lands, circa 1869-1903; M803 (Box A3, Item R7Ag3)
    - Stanford University Campus Map Book, Spring 1999, M804
    - Primary Road System: Existing. April 2, 1965 Overall title: Master Plan for Stanford Lands, M805
    - Primary Road System Inner Campus: Existing Nov. 20, 1964 Overall title: Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1964-11-20; M806
    - Primary Road System: Proposed April 2, 1965 Overall title: Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1965-04-02; M807
    - Primary Road System Inner Campus: proposed Jan. 20, 1965 Overall title: Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1965-01-20; M808
    - Existing Fraternity Row Houses and their Relationship to Approved Campus Development Plans., 1971-04-26; M809
    - Master Plan of Circulation Parking Campus Vicinity. Update, 1978; M810
    - Leland Stanford Junior University. Rev. March 1982 [plan showing roads building shapes from College Terrace to Menlo Park and El Camino to Junipero Serra], 1982-03; M811
    - Proposed land use of academic reserve portion of Stanford lands located in Santa Clara County. A Master Plan for Stanford University. June 10, 1964, copied from the original of Feb. 15, 1961., 1964-06-10; M812
    - Map of the City of Palo Alto, Santa Clara Co., Calif. January 1926 [put out by the Times-Tribune] Shows PA from the creek to Page Mill area, with the campus from El Camino to the Quad., M813
    - South Palo Alto. Real estate pamphlet (C. M. Wooster Company) with birds-eye view of area between Embarcadero and Page Mill. Includes images of Stanford and Palo Alto. Also includes plot for same area., circa 1904; M814
    - Maps of Stanford Campus and Palo Alto Downtown. Published by Stanford Student Enterprises., M817
    - University Park. Town of the LSJU. Morris Mershon Real Estate Agents. Brochure, ca. 1890, showing area between RR, the creek, and Embarcadero Rd.; includes text., M815
    - Radio Field Sites of Stanford University and Stanford Research Institute, 1968-10-24; M818
    - Alignment Study for Foothill Expressway Relocation, 1967, M819
    - Map of Leland Stanford Junior University depicting buildings and spaces for historical preservation, 1967, M820
    - Contour Map, Jasper Ridge Area, 1972; M821
    - Buffer Zone Study, Stanford University. Eldridge T. Spencer, 1955; M822
    - Circulation Study No. 2, Plate 1A, Stanford University. Eldridge T. Spencer, 1959; M823
    - Draft Land Use Plan, Central Campus, 1980-2010, M824
    - Existing Land Use, Central Campus, 1980; M825
    - Index of Sheets for the Master Plan of Campus Development, Leland Stanford Junior University, 1968; M826
    - Map of Leland Stanford Junior University, 1972; M827
    - Jasper Ridge Improvements, 1969; M828
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University [highlighting Searsville Lake Proposal], 1971; M829a
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University [highlighting revisions near Jasper Ridge], 1970; M829b
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University [highlighting revisions to Campus], 1970; M829c
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University [highlighting revisions to Campus], 1970; M829d
    - Condemnation for Widening of Alpine Road, Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University, 1970; M829e
    - Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University, 1968; M829f
    - Location Map of proposed Searsville Addition to Jasper Ridge Biological Preserve, Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University, 1976; M830
    - General Plans of Land Use Based on Policies adopted by Board of Trustees 12 Mar 1974, Lands of Leland Stanford University, M831
    - Potential Housing Sites suggested by Moulton Committee (1969), Wright Committee (1970), Livingston and Blayney (1971), and additional sites under study, Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University, 1978; M832
    - [Map of the Stanford University Campus, undated], 0; M833
    - Adjacent Land Zoning and Proposed Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1961; M834
    - Plan Indicating Proposed Intent of Land Uses, 1953, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1961; M835
    - Extent of Conforming Uses on Non-academic Lands, Compared to Present, Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1961; M836
    - Extent of Conforming Uses on Non-academic Lands, Compared to Present, Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1965; M837
    - Feasibility Study Indicating Possible Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1950; M838
    - Master Plan of Circulation, Streets and Roads, Campus and Vicinity, 1972; M839
    - Proposed Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1953; M840
    - Proposed 1962 Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1961; M841
    - Proposed Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1961; M842
    - Proposed Intent of Land Uses and Primary Road System, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1961; M843
    - Proposed Primary Road System and 1964 Proposed Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, 1965; M844
    - Proposed Primary Road System and 1965 Proposed Intent of Land Uses, Master Plan for Stanford Lands, M845
    - Proposed Road System and Proposed Intent of Land Uses, Inner Campus, 1965; M846
    - Quad and Building Numbers, Stanford University, 1964; M847
    - Campus of Leland Stanford Junior University, 1962; M848
    - [Topographic Sheet from 1902 US Geological Survey identifying Quarries near Stanford Campus, Santa Cruz Quadrangle, California], 1904; M849
    - Stanford Industrial Park, Leland Stanford Junior University, 1970; M850
    - Vehicle Control Plan, Location of Bollard Types, Central Campus, Stanford University, 1979; M851
    - Study for Restricted Area, Scheme II, Stanford University, 1950; M852
    - Study of Alternative Locations for Pathway Lighting suggested for Serra Street Corridor from Campus Drive to El Camino Real, 1979; M853
    - Topographical Map of Stanford University campus and vicinity, M854
  - Properties of LSJU Map Volume, Series 10; 102 item(s)